Finding Aid for the Ray Bolger Papers LSC.1117
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 10. Unidentified Projects, no dates, ca. 1930s-1980s; Boxes 1, 16-28, 31, 33, 37, 50, 54, 57, 74, 76, 79-80, 110
  - Mardi Gras Weekend - revised second draft script, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Masterminds (The) - first draft script, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Memo to Harry Hoff from Frank Wilson regarding Ray Bolger, 1944 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Nervous in the Service - first and second draft scripts, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Never Say Die - script, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - No Longer Innocent - script, no date (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Now Playing Tomorrow - synopsis and script, no date (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Nuts and Bolts - second draft script, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    For pilot episode.
  - Old Poems, no date (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - One Hour of Glory by Mary Roberts Rinehart, no date (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Outside Comin' In - script, 1980-1981 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Palace $2 Vaudeville a Joke - typed article, no date (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Perfect Furlough (The) - script, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Pippin - treatments and script, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Pronunciation aids, no date (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Radio City Music Hall Golden Anniversary - storyboard outline, production material, and correspondence, 1981 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Ray Bolger's Sony meeting remarks, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Ray Wallace Show synopsis, no date (Box 80, Folder 7)
    Does not appear to be related to The Ray Bolger Show/Where's Raymond.
  - Reminders for Books, no date, 1968, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Rhinoceros - script, 1959-1960 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    With photocopied clippings.
  - Ring Horse: A Novel by Thomas Duncan, no date (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Rip van Winkle - synopsis, no date (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Rosalind Regulars (The) - outline, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Ruby Slippers (The) student paper by Todd Machin, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Shire Films - scripts and correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    Scripts for Beware the Jabberwock, The Ugly Duckling, Misty Moisty Morning, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, and Tom Sawyer's Whitewash Job. It is not apparent whether these projects were ever produced.
  - Silver Fire - script, no date (Box 25, Folder 8)
    From the novel Ring Horse by Thomas Duncan.
  - Sketches, bits, ideas and lyrics, no date (Box 25, Folder 3)
    From folder labeled Materials.
  - Sketches, bits, ideas and lyrics, no date (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Slippers - script, no date (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Some Like It Cold! - script, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Songs of Christmas (The) - script, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Sports article featuring Bolger - draft, no date (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Submission letters to Bolger, 1950, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Theresa - shooting script, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Three Thieves (The) - scripts and production costs, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Trunk inventory, no date (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Twenty Years of Rip Van Winkle (The) - synopsis, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Wait for the Dawn: A Play with Music by Gwen Bolger, no date (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Welcome Home - script, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - What About Tomorrow? - treatment and pilot episode script, no date (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Widgin - scripts, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    See also A Calling.
  - Wizard of Oz (The) - music for stage production (folder 2 of 2), no date (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Wizard of Oz (The) - play script (folder 1 of 2), 1968 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Women of Twilight - script, no date (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Wonderful World of Roy Bolger (The), no date (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Wynken Blynken -- and Durante - script, no date (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Zip Goes a Million - published play, 1952, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Series 11. Correspondence, no dates, ca. 1930s-1980s; Boxes 31, 42-50, 80, 131
  The Correspondence series is letters and notes sent to Ray Bolger and/or his wife Gwen Bolger, and is mostly fan mail addressed to Bolger. Also included is correspondence between the Bolgers during WWII, letters or notes to Bolger from notable entertainment and political figures, and personal correspondence from the Bolgers friends and family. There is a very small amount of items related to members of Gwen Bolgers family, the Rickards. The majority of the series is arranged chronologically by decade. Correspondence related to specific projects may be found in the Motion Picture Projects, Stage Projects, Television Projects, and Unidentified Projects series.
  - Cards and invitations to Bolger, no date, ca. 1930s-1970s (Box 80, Folder 2)
    Includes: Bob Hope, Conrad Hilton, Rear Admiral H.A. Yeager, The Harvard Lampoons, and Bing Crosby.
  - Cards and invitations to Bolger from various people, ca. 1930s-1980s (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Children's Theatre Company School regarding suspension of John Clark Donahue, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Get well cards and letters to Bolger, 1981 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Golf correspondence and ephemera, 1960s-1980s (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Greeting cards, 1983-1984 (Box 131, Folder 9)
  - Letters and fan mail to Bolger, no date, 1950s, 1970s-1980s (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Letters from Bolger to Their Royal Highnesses Hassan II and Prince Moulay Abdullah, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Gwen Bolger to Ray Bolger, no date, ca. 1930s-1940s (Box 47, Folder 7)
    22 items.
  - Letters from Gwen Bolger to Ray Bolger, no date, ca. 1930s-1940s (Box 47, Folder 8)
    33 items.
  - Letters from Gwen or Ray Bolger to various people, no date, 1956, 1974-1975 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1940s (Box 44, Folder 5)
    36 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1940s (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1950-1951 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    62 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1952 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    52 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1952 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    63 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1955-1959 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    39 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1960-1961 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    30 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1962 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    34 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1963-1964 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    53 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1965-1969 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1970-1972 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    28 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1970-1972 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1973-1974 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1973-1974 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    35 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1975 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    20 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1975-1976 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1976 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    47 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1977-1979 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    43 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1977-1979 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1980 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1980 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1980 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    38 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1984-1987 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1980-1983 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    Originally from envelope labeled: Fan mail, correspondence. 45 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1984-1986 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Originally from envelope labeled: Fan mail, correspondence. 31 items.
  - Letters to Bolger, no date (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1920s (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1930s (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1940s (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1960s (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1950s (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1970s (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1980s (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1970s (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Bolger, ca. 1980s (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Bolger from school children (with art work), ca. 1970-1972 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Bolger from various correspondents, no date, 1930s-1980s (Box 80, Folder 4)
    Includes: Aaron Spelling, Bing Crosby, Spyros Skouras, George C. Scott, Mayor Norris Poulson.
  - Letters to Bolger regarding appearance requests (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1960s-1980s (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Bolger regarding appearance requests (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1960s-1980s (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Gwen and Ray Bolger from [Fini], no date, 1953, 1961 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Gwen and Ray Bolger from [Pawski], 1951, 1953-1955 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Gwen and Ray Bolger from Helen and Charles Suydam Cutting, no date, 1938, 1950s, 1961-1962 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Gwen and Ray Bolger from Rickard Family, 1932, 1951, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Gwen Bolger from Barbara Boston, 1951-1952, 1954-1955 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Gwen Bolger from various people, no date, 1925, ca. 1930s -1960s, 1980s, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Note to Ray Bolger from Dick Arnold regarding song copies from Wizard of Oz, 1939 (Box 131, Folder 8)
    On ornate Wizard of Oz publicity-type stationary.
  - Notes and photographs regarding amateur Wizard of Oz events, no date, 1979, 1980, 1985 (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - Rickard family letters, no date, late 1940s-early 1950s (Box 42, Folder 8)
    With Air Force photograph of James Rickard.
  - Season's Greetings card, 1942 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Telegrams and well wishes to Bolger, ca. 1931-1936 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Thank you letters to Bolger from various organizations, ca. 1940s-1970s (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Travel in Europe, 1958, 1970s (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Women as Fantasy: Costumes from the Latin Quarter exhibition - correspondence, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 3)
- Series 12. Photographs, no dates, ca. 1920s-1980s; Boxes 103-110, 132, 135
  The Photographs series contains images documenting Bolgers long career in the entertainment indudsty. Included are publicity stills and headshots of Bolger, some identified as MGM, RKO, or ABC productions; photographs of Bolger with other performers and/or public figures; and photographs of Bolger at unidentified functions he attended and/or in which he performed, including golf events, and what appear to be USO-related appearances. Also included are what appear to be personal and publicity photographs of Ray and/or Gwen Bolger, as well as other unidentified individuals. The series is arranged alphabetically by file titles reflecting the contents of each folder. Additional photographs relating to specific projects may be found in the, Motion Picture Projects, Stage Projects, Television Projects, and Unidentified Projects series.
  - ABC publicity stills for Stanley Shapiro for Life Magazine, no date (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Banshees luncheon, 1942 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Bolger at race tracks, 1957-1962 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Bolger at unidentified events, no date (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Bolger in France, no date (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Bolger with Marva Collins at the Westside Prep School, 1982 (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - Bolger with others, no date, ca. 1940s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 4)
    Including Steve Allen, Bing Crosby, Jimmy Durante, Douglas Fairbanks, Alice Faye, Barry Goldwater, Muriel Landers, Tina Louise, Ronald Reagan, and John Wayne.
  - Bolger with others, no date, ca. 1960s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 5)
    Mostly unidentified people and events.
  - Bolger with others, no date (Box 109, Folder 4)
    With one photograph of a theater faade.
  - Bolger with Victor McLaglen, Fred MacMurray, and unidentified, no date (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - Dances, no date (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Desert Inn, 1963 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Dorchester High School Class of 1920 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Early snapshots, no date, 1943 (Box 106, Folder 8)
    Mostly photographs of Ray Bolger.
  - Empire Room, Palmer House - Ray Bolger birthday, 1967 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Golf, no date, ca. 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Golf, no date, ca. 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Golf, no date, 1970, 1972 (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - Gus Edwards Ritz Carlton Nights Revue, 1927-1928 (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Gwen Bolger, no date, 1947 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Headshots of Bolger by James Hargis Connelly, no date (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Headshots of Bolger by Maurice Seymour, no date (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Houses, no date (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Images of Bolger as The Scarecrow, no date (Box 104, Folder 8)
    Headshot (3 items), glass negative, and caricature.
  - Las Vegas News Bureau photographs of Bolger and others, 1956 (Box 125, Folder 16)
    Including Mindy Carson, Jimmy Durante, Cary Grant, Grace Kelly, Tina Louise, Frank Sinatra, and Walter Winchell
  - MGM photographs by Durward Graybill, no date (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Mike Douglas Show (The) photograph album, 1971 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Modern Maturity transparency slides, 1979 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Negatives of set stills, no date (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Oh Teacher, ca. 1928-1929 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of Bolger, no date (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Photograph of Bolger as a boy of sixteen, no date (Box 125, Folder 22)
    Includes negative. See Also Box 51, Folder 6.
  - Photograph of portrait painting of Bolger, no date (Box 106, Folder 10)
    With photographs of portraits of others.
  - Photograph proofs of Bolger dancing, no date (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Photographs for Bride and Home Magazine by Desmond Russell, 1957 (Box 104, Folder 12)
  - Photographs from McFadden, Strauss, Eddy, and Irwin (MSEI), 1965-1967 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Bolger as the Scarecrow, no date (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of others, no date, 1940 (Box 106, Folder 6)
    Mostly unidentified people.
  - Publicity and/or headshots of Bolger, no date, 1926, 1929 (Box 104, Folder 13)
  - Publicity and/or headshots of Bolger, no date (Box 104, Folder 14)
    With duplicate images.
  - Publicity and/or headshots of Bolger, no date (Box 104, Folder 14)
  - Publicity and/or headshots of Bolger, no date (Box 104, Folder 16)
  - Publicity and/or headshots of Bolger, no date, 1960 (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - Publicity and/or headshots of Bolger, no date, 1972, 1974-1975, 1979 (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - Publicity photographs of Bolger, no date (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Publicity photographs of Ray Bolger, no date (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Ray and Gwen Bolger, no date, 1930s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - Ray Bolger with Maurice Chevalier and Muriel Landers, 1965 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    One autographed photo by Maurice Chevalier not included in the original envelope.
  - Reno Sparks Nugget, 1964 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    Removed images from Box 50 Folder 16 for preservation purposes. See also Clippings series (Box 50, Folder 16).
  - RKO stills, no date, 1941 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Romantic Nights, no date (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Scotch Buy stills, no date (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Snapshots, no date, 1960s-1980s (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - Souvenir photograph of Bolger, no date (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Souvenir photographs, no date (Box 106, Folder 7)
    Ray Bolger, Gwen Bolger, and others.
  - Sweethearts, 1938 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Ten Around Town, 1965 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified performances, no date (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified publicity photographs, no date (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Voice of the Army, 1949 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Wardrobe shots, no date (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Wizard of Oz copy stills and published interview with Margaret Hamilton, 1984 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Zeni photographs of unidentified performance, 1964 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    One photo with Desi Arnaz and other unidentified people. May be from Palm Springs.
- Series 13. Clippings, no dates, ca. 1930s-1980s; Boxes 16, 33-37, 50, 132
  The Clippings series a mixture of publicity and promotional write-ups about appearances and events in which Bolger was involved and articles written about Bolger, often referencing his role in the Wizard of Oz. There are also a small number of items pertaining to Gwen Bolger. The series is arranged alphabetically by file titles reflecting the contents of each folder. General clippings about Bolger are listed first. Clippings related to specific projects may be found in the, Motion Picture Projects, Stage Projects, Television Projects, and Unidentified Projects series.
  - Clippings relating to Bolger, no date (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Clippings relating to Bolger, ca. 1920s-1930s (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Clippings relating to Bolger, ca. 1970s (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Clippings relating to Bolger, ca. 1980s (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Clippings relating to Gwen Bolger, 1940, 1942, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Clippings relating to others in entertainment, 1979, 1984, no date (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - 1976 Academy Awards (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Ames Club, Houston, 1962-1963 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Bell Hour, etc., 1964 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Boys Club of Minneapolis Benefit, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Chez Paree, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Clippings related to Bolger, no date, 1947-1953 (Box 132, Folder 5)
  - Clippings relating to Bolger, ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Clippings relating to Bolger, ca. 1960s (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Coconut Grove, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Garden State Arts Center Big Show of 1936, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Joke clippings, no date, 1940, 1942 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Keep Off the Grass, 1940 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Magazine tear-outs, no date, 1948, 1951 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Michigan Theater, ca. 1940s (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - President's Birthday Ball, 1938 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Reno Sparks Nugget appearance, 1964 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    Removed photographs for preservation purposes. See Photographs series (Box 104, Folder 3).
  - Rheingold clippings and stills, 1957, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Santa Fe Film Festival, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Who's Who in America, 1955 (Box 125, Folder 17)
- Series 14. Ephemera, no dates, ca. 1940s-1980s; Boxes 37-40, 51, 75, 110-113, 115
  The Ephemera series consists of advertising ephemera; publications mentioning or featuring Bolger; programs, playbills, and/or ephemera from appearances and events Bolger may have attended; and sketches and drawings of Bolger in and out of character, some depicting him as the Scarecrow. Additionally there is a small amount of business cards and entertainment publications that do not appear to be related to Bolger.
  - Advertising ephemera, no date, 1929, 1935, 1950, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Al Hirschfeld artwork of Bolger, no date (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Appearances and events attended, no date, 1929, 1940s-1960s (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Appearances and events attended - ephemera, no date, 1950s-1970s (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Appearances and events attended - ephemera, no date, 1940s-1970s (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Business cards, no date (Box 75)
  - Drawings of Bolger, no date (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Life of a Scarecrow: The Most Popular Man in Oz sketches by Kate Kennedy and additional sketch, 1942 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Magnetic Recorders bill of sale and publications, no date (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Playbills, no date, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 112)
  - Playbills and Las Vegas magazines, no date, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 111)
  - Publications featuring or mentioning Bolger (A), 1976, 1978 1980 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Publications featuring or mentioning Bolger (A-N), ca. 1950s-1980s (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Publications featuring or mentioning Bolger (C-O), no date, ca. 1930s-1940s, 1960s-1980s (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Publications featuring or mentioning Bolger (M-Z), ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Publications featuring or mentioning Bolger (R-S), no date, ca. 1940s -1980s (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Publications featuring or mentioning Bolger (T-Z), 1941, 1960s, 1975, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Scroll written in Latin, no date (Box 122)
  - Sketch of Bolger by Pierotti, no date (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Television guides mentioning Bolger, ca. 1950s-1970s (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Theater publication, no date, 1929, 1951, 1954, 1962 (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Theater, film, and music publications, no date, 1945, 1949, 1972 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    Mostly theater publications.
- Series 15. Awards, Honors, and Affiliations, no dates, ca. 1930s-1980s; Boxes 28, 41-42, 50, 53, 72, 110
  The series consists of award and honor certificates bestowed upon Bolger from a wide range of organizations, clubs, orders, and associations, including an honorary degree from the University of Connecticut. Also included are membership cards and certificates for various clubs and organizations. There is no specific arrangement to the series.
  - American Physical Fitness Research Institute Care Award, 1974 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Appreciation of public service certificate, 1949 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Awards and Certificates, ca. 1950s, 1970s-1980s (Box 125, Folder 20)
  - Awards, certificates, and honors, 1930s-1980s (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Bel Air Country Club, 1980 (Box 53)
  - Bohemian Grove - ephemera and correspondence, ca. 1950s-1980s (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Bohemian Grove - ephemera and correspondence, no date, 1959, 1967-1968, 1979 (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Bolger's membership cards and certificates for various organizations, no date, ca. 1950s,1970s-1980s (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Boys Club of Hollywood, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Cypress College bicentennial tribute, 1976 (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - Film Welfare league Outstanding Showmanship Award, 1983 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Sovereign Military Order of Malta - ephemera and correspondence, 1969, ca. 1980s (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Theater Hall of Fame honor, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - University of Connecticut - correspondence and clippings, 1975-1977, early 1980s (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - University of Connecticut convocation photo album, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 1)
- Series 16. Business, Legal, and Financial Records, no dates, ca. 1930s-1980s; Boxes 57, 74-80, 110, 119
  The Business, Legal, and Financial records consist mainly of contracts and financial documents representing a variety of projects in which Bolger was involved throughout his career. Included are agreements with studios such as CBS, KNBC, and NBC, commercial companies, and live venue locations such as Cocoanut Grove and Hotel Sahara, among others. Of note are a photocopy of Bolgers agreement from July 1939 with respect to commercial tie-ups of Wizard of Oz properties and a copy of the term agreement Bolger had with MGM in April of 1936. The financial documents reflect the operations of B&R Enterprises and other business ventures. The series is arranged alphabetically by file titles reflecting the contents of each folder. A small number of contracts regarding specific projects may be found in the Motion Picture Projects, Stage Projects, Television Projects, and Unidentified Projects series.
  - AAA Bowling Center - venture agreement and annual reports, 1959-1961, 1963 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Actor Equity Association booklets regarding benefits and pension, 1966 (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - AFTRA Code, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - American Broadcasting Company contract, Apr 1953 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    Possibly for The Ray Bolger Show.
  - American Coating Company Sparkle trademark, Apr 1952 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - American Federation of Musicians payment regarding Ray Bolger Show music, 1954 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - B&R Enterprises - summary of cash received and disbursed, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - B&R Enterprises - summary of cash received and disbursed, 1961 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - B&R Enterprises, Inc. - minutes of meetings, 1969 (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Bolger vs. RKO, May 1951 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Business letters to keep, ca. 1950s, 1960 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Capricorn Stable, 1960 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Contracts, 1923-1936 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    Includes: MGM, Paramount, Shubert Theatrical Company, Bob Ott Company.